Yauheni Baltukha

evgenii.boltuho@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/baltuky | github.com/baltuky

SUMMARY

I have over 7 years of experience as a software engineer, and have worked at both small and large companies. While I'm a data engineer, my expertise is in building scalable and reliable back-end services (API services, data pipelines). I love building things. While hard engineering problems are often intrinsically fun to tackle.

EXPERIENCE

Senior SWE Nov 2019 – Mar 2021

Lyft

Minsk

- Implemented multi-versioning Protobuf schema support for Apache Flink consumer applications.
- Designed and developed a CLI tool to manage data pipelines.
- Designed a service to materialize collected on S3 data into Presto tables.
- Helm charts for Presto as well as for the Hive Metastore components.

Senior SWEJul 2019 – Nov 2019

Juno

- Minsk
- Designed and developed Flink's source/sink components to backup Apache Kafka data on a remote file system.
- Developed Flink's Kudu sink to support writing data into Kudu.
- Apache Airflow pipelines to periodically backup Kudu databases.
- Kudu Flink Catalog to make data accessible from the Flink's Table API.

Senior SWE Nov 2015 – May 2019

EPAM Systems

Minsk

- Designing and developing batch/streaming Spark applications in Scala to process lithography data.
- Creating Kibana dashboards to help processing engineers improve manufacturing cycle.
- Working closely with data analyst/process engineers to gather and analyze requirements.
- Mentoring and developing junior and mid-level software engineers.

Projects

Data collection platform for events analytics | Scala, Flink, K8s, AWS, Presto

May 2020 - Present

- Designed and developed a Flink service to consume and store analytics events.
- Explored a ways to make data materialization into Presto tables along with managing schemas of Presto tables.

Data Analytics Platform | Scala, Spark, Kafka, ELK, AWS

Sep 2018 – Mar 2019

- Created a set of Kibana dashboards to visualize lithography logs.
- Develop Spark batch/streaming application to process lithography logs and load them to ElasticSearch.

Hotel loyalty system | Java, Oracle, Spring Framework, GWT

Nov 2015 – Sep 2017

- Designed and developed a service to process and manage promo codes.
- Integrated GWT UI application with server-side to manage promo codes.
- Developed load-tests using Gatling.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Scala

Technologies: Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, AWS, Apache Flink, Docker, K8s

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics

Minsk, BY

Bachelor

Sep. 2013 - Jun 2017